<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Book 1: Magic Items S</name>
		<description>The first published work</description>
		<update version="0.0.2">
			<file name="book-1-items-s.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tel0k/Aurora-Builder-Griffon-s-Saddlebag/main/elements/Griffon-s-Saddlebag/Griffon-s-Book-1/book-1-items-s.xml"/>
		</update>
	</info>
<!-- 73 items -->
	<element name="Sandstorm Dancer" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SANDSTORM_DANCER">
		<description>
			<p>This golden cloak billows illusory sand around you when you walk or cast a spell. The cloak has 8 charges and regains 1d6 + 2 expended charges daily at dawn. While wearing the cloak, you can expend 1 or more of its charges to cast the following spells from it (save DC 15): <i>blur</i> (2 charges), <i>call lightning</i> (3 charges), <i>create or destroy water</i> (1 charge), or <i>hallucinatory terrain</i> (4 charges).</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Scholar's Cap (Uncommon)" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SCHOLARS_CAP_UNCOMMON">
		<description>
			<p>This hat carries with it the cleverness and knowledge of many previous scholars. While wearing the hat, you gain a +1 bonus to Intelligence checks and saving throws.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, when it would normally take you at least 1 week in order to research a subject, you instead finish that research 1 day faster for each week you would have spent.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="intelligence:save:misc" value="1"/>
			<stat name="arcana:misc" value="1"/>
			<stat name="history:misc" value="1"/>
			<stat name="investigation:misc" value="1"/>
			<stat name="nature:misc" value="1"/>
			<stat name="religion:misc" value="1"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Scholar's Cap (Rare)" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SCHOLARS_CAP_RARE">
		<description>
			<p>This hat carries with it the cleverness and knowledge of many previous scholars. While wearing the hat, you gain a +2 bonus to Intelligence checks and saving throws.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, when it would normally take you at least 1 week in order to research a subject, you instead finish that research 2 days faster for each week you would have spent.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="intelligence:save:misc" value="2"/>
			<stat name="arcana:misc" value="2"/>
			<stat name="history:misc" value="2"/>
			<stat name="investigation:misc" value="2"/>
			<stat name="nature:misc" value="2"/>
			<stat name="religion:misc" value="2"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Scholar's Cap (Very Rare)" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SCHOLARS_CAP_VERYRARE">
		<description>
			<p>This hat carries with it the cleverness and knowledge of many previous scholars. While wearing the hat, you gain either a +3 bonus to Intelligence checks and saving throws.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, when it would normally take you at least 1 week in order to research a subject, you instead finish that research 3 days faster for each week you would have spent.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="intelligence:save:misc" value="3"/>
			<stat name="arcana:misc" value="3"/>
			<stat name="history:misc" value="3"/>
			<stat name="investigation:misc" value="3"/>
			<stat name="nature:misc" value="3"/>
			<stat name="religion:misc" value="3"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Scorching Cleaver" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SCORCHING_CLEAVER">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. This battleaxe has 8 charges and regains 1d6 + 2 expended charges each day at dawn. As long as the weapon has at least 1 charge, attacks you make with it deal an extra 1d6 fire damage to any target it hits. When you roll a 20 on an attack roll made with this weapon, it regains 3 expended charges.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Erupting Slash.</i></b> As an action, you can expend 3 or more of the battleaxe's charges to slash the air in front you. When you do, a line of fire 30 feet long and 5 feet wide erupts from the blade. Creatures within the line must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 1d6 fire damage for each expended charge. If you expend 4 or more charges in this way and leave the battleaxe with 0 remaining charges, the weapon overheats. When it overheats, targets within the line take an extra 3d6 fire damage, and creatures that succeed on the Dexterity saving throw take half damage instead of avoiding the effect. The DC for this property's saving throw is equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + the number of charges you expend.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="battleaxe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Battleaxe</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Screaming Longbow" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SCREAMING_LONGBOW">
		<description>
			<p>Arrows fired from this sickly longbow let out a screeching howl audible up to 100 feet away as they fly by. Creatures struck by these arrows take an extra 2d4 thunder damage. When you roll a 20 on an attack roll made with this weapon, all creatures within 5 feet of the target must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or be deafened for 1 minute.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longbow">Weapon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longbow</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sea Serpent Hairpin" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SEA_SERPENT_HAIRPIN">
		<description>
			<p>This golden, twisting hair pin wraps around a tiny silver sword and gives your fingers and skin a slight grip while underwater. While wearing this pin, you have advantage on Strength (Athletics) checks you make in order to grapple another creature while you are either submerged or swimming in water.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Seafarer's Jacket" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SEAFARERS_JACKET">
		<description>
			<p>This long captain's jacket carries with it an air of authority. Water slides off of it with ease and magically enhances your comfort in the ocean. You gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed while wearing the jacket as well as proficiency with water vehicles and navigator's tools. If you already have proficiency with water vehicles and navigator's tools, your proficiency bonus is doubled when using them. In addition, you can use the jacket to cast the fog cloud spell at 2nd level. Once the jacket has been used to cast this spell, it can't be used to cast the spell again until the following dawn.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed:swim" value="speed"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_NAVIGATORS_TOOLS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_VEHICLES_WATER" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Seat Belt" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SEAT_BELT">
		<description>
			<p>While standing on a solid surface, you can begin to sit down in an open space as if there were a chair beneath you. When you would normally crouch or fall to the ground when doing this, you can mentally command the belt to summon an invisible, incorporeal chair as a bonus action instead. The chair can be of any style you choose, such as a stool, recliner, throne, or rocking chair, and can support up to 500 pounds. While it is comfortable, it is nevertheless invisible, and cannot be interacted with beyond simply sitting on. The chair disappears if it is no longer on a solid surface, you stand up, or if you're pushed or moved while sitting on it.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Seed of Rebirth" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SEED_OF_REBIRTH">
		<description>
			<p>This fist-sized, magic seed can be attuned to by up to 4 creatures over the course of a long rest. Each creature attuned to the seed must participate in gently planting it in fertile soil. The seed immediately begins to flourish, growing into a majestic, flowering tree over the course of 7 days. The tree is 60 feet tall and 5 feet in diameter at its base, and its canopy extends out in a 30-foot radius from the center of the tree. The tree has a number of large limbs equal to the number of creatures attuned to the seed. Once planted in this way, no other creatures can attune to the seed. Your attunement to the seed is broken early if you commit a malicious affront to nature.</p>
			<p class="indent">When a creature attuned to the seed dies and remains dead for 1 minute, its soul returns to the tree and its body crumbles into a rich soil that recreates the <i>plant growth</i> spell, centered on the body. The soul returns to the tree regardless of the circumstance, distance, or plane of existence of the creature's death. The returned soul is stored in a shelled nut that the tree grows at the time of the creature's death. After 1d6 + 1 days, the nut falls from the tree and breaks apart, revealing the reborn creature inside. The creature is reborn as if by the <i>reincarnate</i> spell. Once a creature is reborn in this way, its attunement to the seed is broken.</p>
			<p class="indent">When a creature's attunement to the seed is broken, the branch associated with that creature withers and dies. The tree is magical and can't be destroyed by nonmagical means. If the tree is destroyed, all creatures attuned to the seed are no longer attuned to it. Any creature attuned to the seed is magically alerted if the tree is being attacked or destroyed, or if one of the branches begins to wither. Once all of the tree's branches wither in this way or are destroyed, the tree splits apart and disintegrates, releasing another <i>seed of rebirth</i> to the astral winds that carry it to a new location on a different plane of existence.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Septum Ring of the Great Minotaur" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SEPTUM_RING_OFTHE_GREAT_MINOTAUR">
		<description>
			<p>This septum barbell is made from tempered gold and studded with rubies. While wearing this ring as a nose piercing, your Strength score increases by 2, to a maximum of 22, and you have advantage on Strength checks. In addition, your carrying capacity doubles, and you can perfectly recall any path you've traveled within the last 24 hours.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<element name="Capacity Count As Larger Size" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_WEIGHT_CAPACITY_COUNTS_AS_LARGER" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE"/>
			<stat name="strength" value="2"/>
			<stat name="strength:max" value="22"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Serpent Dart" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SERPENT_DART">
		<description>
			<p>You can use an action to cause thick, emerald green poison to coat this magic dart. The poison remains for 1 minute or until an attack using this weapon hits a creature. That creature must succeed on a DC 13 Constitution saving throw or take an extra 2d8 poison damage from the attack and become poisoned for 1 minute. Once this property has been used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="dart">Weapon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dart</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Servitude Choker" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SERVITUDE_CHOKER">
		<description>
			<p>This necklace can animate small nonliving objects and have them fulfill simple tasks for you. As an action, you can drape or wrap the necklace around a Small or smaller nonmagical object that weighs less than 50 pounds and isn't attached to or carried by anything else. The adorned object springs to life, sprouting little arms and legs, and becomes a mindless creature under your control until you remove the necklace or it takes damage. The servant has an AC of 10 and a movement speed of 20 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can mentally command the servant if it's within 60 feet of you. The servant can perform simple tasks that a human servant could do, such as fetching things, cleaning, mending, folding clothes, lighting fires, serving food, and pouring wine. The servant can't attack, activate magic items, or carry more than 10 pounds. Once you give it a command, the servant performs the task to the best of its ability until it completes the task, then waits for your next command. If you command the servant to perform a task that would put it in danger or move it more than 60 feet away from you, the servant does nothing.</p>
			<p class="indent">The necklace can animate an object for up to 8 hours or until it takes damage. When the effect ends, the necklace can't be used again for another 1d8 hours.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Set of Numat's Trick Tubes" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SET_OF_NUMATS_TRICK_TUBES">
		<description>
			<p>This drab pair of empty ceramic cylinders are magically linked. Each vessel is 3 inches in diameter and 1 foot tall. Placing an item inside one of the vessels and closing the lid will magically teleport it to the second tube, making a quiet whoosh sound when it does. A similarly quiet thud can be heard when receiving an item. A tube can't send more than 2 pounds of material at a time and can't be used to send a creature. Both vessels must be on the same plane of existence and have their lids closed in order for an item to be teleported between them.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Set of Secret Scribe Candles" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SET_OF_SECRET_SCRIBE_CANDLES">
		<description>
			<p>This pair of candles are magically linked and never seems to run out of wick.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can light one of the candles to cause it to burn with a blue flame. By holding parchment over the flame, any ink on the page is burnt off, leaving the paper unmarked. When you finish using the candle in this way, you can extinguish the flame as you normally would. Once you do, the linked candle suddenly comes alight with a normal, orange fire, that cannot be extinguished by nonmagical means. The newly lit candle gives off a faint lavender scent. By holding a plain piece of parchment over the orange flame, the ink from the first piece of parchment is magically burnt onto the new one as the candle heats it. Once all the ink has been transcribed onto new parchment in this way, the orange flame winks out.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shadow Drinker" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SHADOW_DRINKER">
		<description>
			<p>This wicked dagger can absorb the shadows cast by your enemies. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you hit a Small or larger hostile creature with a melee attack using this dagger, you can choose to absorb that creature's shadow as part of the attack. When you do, that creature no longer casts a shadow, and the dagger becomes shrouded in a dark haze that extends to you while you hold the dagger. While this haze is also surrounding you, you are invisible in areas of dim light and darkness.</p>
			<p class="indent">The dark haze surrounds the dagger for 10 minutes or until you end it as a bonus action. The haze ends early after you attack or cast a spell. If a creature is hit by the dagger while it's shrouded in this haze, the creature takes an extra 1d6 psychic damage from the attack. This bonus damage increases to 2d6 if the creature hit by the dagger is missing its shadow. Once the haze ends, the shadow immediately returns to the creature from whom it was taken.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can only have 1 shadow absorbed in this way at a time. Once you steal a creature's shadow, you can't steal that same creature's shadow again until the following dusk.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Curse.</i></b> You have vulnerability to radiant damage while you're attuned to this weapon.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_VULNERABILITY_RADIANT" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Shadow Ink" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SHADOW_INK">
		<description>
			<p>Once penned, this special ink can only be seen and read in total darkness. When in darkness, any written or tattooed words, illustrations, or other marks made with this ink glow with a soft, colored light. One bottle of <i>shadow ink</i> has enough ink to fill 10 pages with writing, illustrations, or other such markings.</p>
			<p class="indent">A <i>detect magic</i> spell reveals only that there is something faintly magical about the area where this ink has been used, but does not reveal the kind of magic or how to interact with it.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shadow Ward" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SHADOW_WARD">
		<description>
			<p>This eerily still cloak seems to absorb some of the light that touches it. While wearing this cloak, you have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks. In addition, the cloak has 3 charges and regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dusk. When you're hit by an attack, you can use a reaction to expend 1 of the cloak's charges to halve the damage you take from the attack and teleport in a plume of black smoke to an unoccupied space you can see within 30 feet of you.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shadowshawl" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SHADOWSHAWL">
		<description>
			<p>This light gray shawl is made of thick fabric that looks like woven spider webs. While wearing this shawl with its hood up, your face is hidden within a small pocket of magical darkness. You can see through this darkness from beneath the hood as if it were nonmagical. If you have the Sunlight Sensitivity trait, you are unaffected by the trait while the hood is up. Pulling the hood up or down requires an action.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shadowsmoke Dragon Pipe" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SHADOWSMOKE_DRAGON_PIPE">
		<description>
			<p>This magic pipe leaves behind odorless smoke that dissipates quickly. Its head easily detaches, allowing you to refill it. The pipe has 4 charges and regains 1d3 + 1 expended charges daily at dawn. As an action, you can expend 1 charge to blow a small, condensed smoke ring at a friendly creature (including yourself) that you can see within 30 feet of you.</p>
			<p class="indent">A creature can immediately turn invisible when it's affected by the smoke (no action required) or choose to wear the smoke as if it were a physical ring. This ring lasts for 1 minute or until the creature uses a bonus action on one of its turns to turn invisible. A creature turned invisible by the smoke ring reappears at the start of its next turn or when it attacks or cast a spell. A creature can only have 1 smoke ring at any time.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shaedenstaff" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SHAEDENSTAFF">
		<description>
			<p>This staff is made from the reclaimed horn of a huge undead creature. While you're attuned to the staff, you have advantage on saving throws to retain your sanity against the influence of environment effects. The staff can also be used as a magic quarterstaff.</p>
			<p class="indent">The staff has 15 charges for the following properties and regains 2d6 + 3 expended charges daily at dusk. If you expend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the staff disintegrates in a plume of pitch black smoke and emits a terrifying scream audible out to 300 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Annihilating Strike.</i></b> When you hit with a melee attack using the staff, you can expend 1 charge to deal an extra 1d10 necrotic damage to the target.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Spells.</i></b> While holding the staff, you can use an action to expend 1 or more of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it, using your spell save DC: <i>calm emotions</i> (1 charge), <i>darkness</i> (2 charges), <i>dispel evil and good</i> (5 charges), <i>inflict wounds</i> (3rd-level version, 3 charges), or <i>circle of death</i> (6 charges).</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a sorcerer, warlock, or wizard">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shapeshifter's Circlet" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SHAPESHIFTERS_CIRCLET">
		<description>
			<p>This ivory circlet allows you to recreate some of the natural features of other creatures. While wearing the circlet, you can spend 1 minute to gently massage your ears, forehead, or temples. When you do, you can choose to create one of the following features or effects:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You can cover or replace your own ears with the form of another creature's.</li>
				<li>You can summon one or more horns or antlers atop your head.</li>
				<li>You can change the appearance of your eyes, including their color and pupil shape.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>You can only have 1 of these effects active at a time. The effect lasts until you dismiss it as a bonus action, remove the circlet, or fall unconscious. You don't gain any of the senses or abilities of another creature by recreating its physical features in this way.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shared Burden" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SHARED_BURDEN">
		<description>
			<p>This set of chained rings and bracers is a sign of the pact you forged with your patron. When you attune to the item, the small spikes that line the inside of the bands become harmless and feel like a warm, gentle caress against your skin. Once attuned, you can also use it as a spellcasting focus.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever you would deal damage to a creature with a warlock spell or cantrip, you can choose to add your Charisma modifier (minimum 1) to the spell's damage. When you do, you take psychic damage equal to half your Charisma modifier (minimum 1), rounded up. This psychic damage ignores resistances and immunities.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a warlock">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sharkrazor Mantle" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SHARKRAZOR_MANTLE">
		<description>
			<p>While wearing this magic shark-skinned cloak, you have a swimming speed of 60 feet and can breathe underwater. When a creature successfully grapples or restrains you by touching you, that creature takes 1d6 piercing damage. A creature takes this damage again at the start of each of its turns while it maintains this grapple or restraint.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, while wearing the cloak, you have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) and Wisdom (Survival) checks made to find or track a creature that's missing any of its hit points, and when you attack a creature you can't see that's below its hit point maximum, you make the attack as if you can see it.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed:swim" value="60"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Sheer Cold" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SHEER_COLD">
		<description>
			<p>The blade of this battleaxe is made from a shard of the Everglacier and never melts. Attacks with the axe deal cold damage instead of slashing, and you gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you roll a 20 on an attack roll with this weapon, the ground in the direction of the target in either a 15-foot cone or 30-foot-long, 5-foot-wide line (your choice) is covered in a layer of slick ice for 1 minute, making it difficult terrain. When a creature enters this area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it must succeed on a DC 10 Dexterity saving throw or fall prone. In addition, the original target of the attack must succeed on a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw or be restrained by ice until the start of your next turn. The restrained target can use an action to make a DC 15 Strength check. On a success, the target is freed.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">battleaxe</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="battleaxe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Battleaxe</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shield of Yggdrasil" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SHIELD_OF_YGGDRASIL">
		<requirements>[str:17]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You must have a Strength of 17 or higher in order to wield this massive, magical tower shield. The shield is of dwarven make and functions as a small battlement, granting you an additional +1 bonus to your AC while you wield it. This bonus is in addition to the shield's normal bonus to AC.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Shield plant.</i></b> As a bonus action, you can plant this shield on the ground to barricade yourself behind it, granting you half cover against ranged attacks from the direction you're facing. While you wield the planted shield, bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage you take from nonmagical weapons is reduced by 3, but your movement speed becomes 5 feet. You can uproot the shield to end this effect as an action.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can doff the shield when planting it by using an action to do so instead of a bonus action. The shield magically remains upright and in place and can be used as half cover to any creature standing immediately behind it in the space it was left in. The shield falls down when you fall unconscious or when knocked over following a successful DC 20 Strength (Athletics) check. You can move the shield while it's planted by donning the shield again.</p>
			<p class="indent">This shield has 3 charges and regains all expended charges each day at dawn. You can expend 1 charge when you plant this shield or later on a subsequent turn as a bonus action to send out metal roots along the ground in a 10-foot radius, centered on the shield. Enemy creatures treat this area as difficult terrain. Moving the shield also moves the roots. The roots remain until you uproot the shield or it falls over.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shield</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shielding Turtle Sugarbombs" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SHIELDING_TURTLE_SUGARBOMBS">
		<description>
			<p>These sticky chocolate candies are filled with an enchanted molasses and caramel center and come in packs of 2. You can eat one of these sugarbombs as an action. When you do, your movement speed is reduced by 10 feet for 1 minute. If you are proficient with shields and are wearing one on your back, you gain a +1 bonus to your AC while your speed is reduced in this way. If you're wielding a shield, you don't gain this bonus to your AC.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Upset stomach.</i></b> You can only be under the effects of 1 sugarbomb that has this feature at a time. Eating a sugarbomb that has this feature while under the effects of another one causes the effects of the first sugarbomb to immediately end and be replaced by the new one's. This rapid change is difficult to stomach, forcing you to make a DC 13 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, you gain the effects of the new sugarbomb, but become poisoned for 1 minute. On a success, you gain the effects of the new sugarbomb and are not poisoned.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Signet Rings of Blindness, Deafness, and Silence" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SIGNET_RINGS_OF_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS_AND_SILENCE">
		<description>
			<p>Each of these three signets is decorated with the carving of a skull and a pair of skeletal hands that cover either its eyes (blindness), ears (deafness), or mouth (in an area of silence). Each ring has 1 charge, which it regains each day at dawn. If you are wearing the corresponding signet when you are blinded, deafened, or in an area of magical silence, you can expend the ring's charge (no action required) to be cured of the condition or speak a word or phrase (such as a verbal arcane components) that can be heard through magical silence. Wearing the rings together as a set combines their collective charges: potentially allowing you to use one ring's properties multiple times.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Rings</set>
			<set name="type">Ring</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">ring</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Signet Rings of the Fey Court" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SIGNET_RINGS_OFTHE_FEY_COURT">
		<description>
			<p>This set of wooden rings once belonged to a powerful fey creature who ruled over a domain on their native plane of existence. You must be wearing all four rings in order to attune to and use their magic. While wearing the rings, you know the <i>druidcraft</i> cantrip. In addition, you gain the elf's Trance racial trait if you don't already have it.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Season's Resistance.</i></b> Each of the four rings has a corresponding season: autumn, spring, summer, or winter. Each ring contains 2 charges and regains all expended charges when you finish a long rest. You can expend 1 of a particular ring's charges as a reaction when you take damage of a type corresponding to that ring in order to gain resistance to that damage type until the start of your next turn, including against the triggering effect: autumn (necrotic damage resistance), spring (radiant damage resistance), summer (fire damage resistance), or winter (cold damage resistance).</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Magic Resistance.</i></b> Alternatively, you can expend any 2 charges from the rings as a reaction when you're affected by a hostile spell or other magical effect in order to gain advantage on saving throws against spells and magical effects until the start of your next turn. The 2 charges do not need to be from the same ring.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once a ring has no remaining charges, the small landscape adorning the top of it withers until it regains its charges.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">ring</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_TRANCE" requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACE_ELF,!ID_RACE_ELF,!ID_WOTC_MOTM_RACE_SEA_ELF"/>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_TRANCE" requirements="!ID_RACE_ELF,!ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACE_ELF,!ID_WOTC_MOTM_RACE_SEA_ELF"/>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_MOTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_SEA_ELF_TRANCE" requirements="!ID_WOTC_PHB24_RACE_ELF,!ID_RACE_ELF,!ID_WOTC_MOTM_RACE_SEA_ELF"/>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT" requirements="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_PLAYERS_HANDBOOK,!ID_WOTC_SOURCE_PLAYERS_HANDBOOK_2024" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_PHB24_SPELL_DRUIDCRAFT" requirements="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_PLAYERS_HANDBOOK_2024" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Silken Socks of Slickening" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SILKEN_SOCKS_OF_SLICKENING">
		<description>
			<p>This pair of magic, smooth socks are iridescent and oily to the touch. While wearing both socks on your feet, you can use them to cast the <i>grease</i> spell as an action (save DC 13). When you do, the spell targets a 10-foot square area adjacent to you. The magical oil runs off the socks to the ground at your feet, causing the ground to become slick. Once used, this property of the socks can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">feet</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Silver Eagle Weapon (Greataxe)" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SILVER_EAGLE_WEAPON_GREATAXE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with these silvered, magic weapons of elven make. These weapons deal 2d6 damage instead of their normal damage dice, and landing a critical hit with the weapon doesn't double the weapon's damage dice. Whenever you land an attack with the weapon and roll the same number on both of the weapon's damage dice, you can immediately roll another d6 and add it to the weapon's damage dice. You can continue rolling extra damage dice until you roll a number that does not match the previous rolls.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">greataxe</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greataxe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greataxe</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Silver Eagle Weapon (Greatsword)" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SILVER_EAGLE_WEAPON_GREATSWORD">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with these silvered, magic weapons of elven make. These weapons deal 2d6 damage instead of their normal damage dice, and landing a critical hit with the weapon doesn't double the weapon's damage dice. Whenever you land an attack with the weapon and roll the same number on both of the weapon's damage dice, you can immediately roll another d6 and add it to the weapon's damage dice. You can continue rolling extra damage dice until you roll a number that does not match the previous rolls.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">greatsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greatsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greatsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Silver Eagle Weapon (Lance)" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SILVER_EAGLE_WEAPON_LANCE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with these silvered, magic weapons of elven make. These weapons deal 2d6 damage instead of their normal damage dice, and landing a critical hit with the weapon doesn't double the weapon's damage dice. Whenever you land an attack with the weapon and roll the same number on both of the weapon's damage dice, you can immediately roll another d6 and add it to the weapon's damage dice. You can continue rolling extra damage dice until you roll a number that does not match the previous rolls.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">lance</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="lance">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Lance</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Silver Eagle Weapon (Maul)" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SILVER_EAGLE_WEAPON_MAUL">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with these silvered, magic weapons of elven make. These weapons deal 2d6 damage instead of their normal damage dice, and landing a critical hit with the weapon doesn't double the weapon's damage dice. Whenever you land an attack with the weapon and roll the same number on both of the weapon's damage dice, you can immediately roll another d6 and add it to the weapon's damage dice. You can continue rolling extra damage dice until you roll a number that does not match the previous rolls.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">maul</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="maul">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Maul</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Silver Lycan Chime" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SILVER_LYCAN_CHIME">
		<description>
			<p>This small silver bell exudes divination magic, especially while under a full moon. When hung, the bell rings a unique, magical melody if a shapechanger passes no more than 15 feet underneath it. Different kinds of shapechangers cause the bell to emit a different sound. The melody is quiet but is nevertheless audible out to 100 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">Under a full moon, the range of the bell's magic changes. During a full moon, any shapechanger within 60 feet of the bell causes it to play its melody.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Singing Stein" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SINGING_STEIN">
		<description>
			<p>While this pewter stein holds at least a sip's worth of potable alcohol, the face adorning it comes alive to sing songs based on the kind of drink. The stein is not sentient, but does have a pleasant singing voice. If there are multiple steins in the same room, they can sing together in harmony if they have the same drinks within them.</p>
			<p class="indent">The stein sings songs slightly out of key if the drink inside is poisoned, which can be heard following a successful Wisdom (Perception) check as determined by the GM. If there are multiple kinds of alcohol within it, the stein either alternates between song types or does its best to combine their various lyrics.</p>
			<h5>title</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="col-10">Example drink</td><td>Type of song</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Wine</td><td>Ballad</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Rum</td><td>Sea Shanty</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Ale</td><td>Drinking song</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sirensong Silencer" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SIRENSONG_SILENCER">
		<description>
			<p>You can place this golden ear cuff over your ear as an action. While wearing the cuff, you have advantage on saving throws against being charmed. In addition, tapping the ear cuff twice deafens you, although you can still faintly hear the sound of the ocean (no action required). Tapping the cuff twice again allows you to hear normally once more.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sling of the Tiny Giant" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SLING_OFTHE_TINY_GIANT">
		<description>
			<p>This wicked sling is devastating against foes larger than yourself. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon, and when you hit a creature with a ranged attack using this sling, the creature takes an extra 1d4 force damage for each size larger than you it is (up to an extra 3d4 damage).</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, when you roll a 20 on an attack roll made with the sling, the target must succeed on a DC 15 Strength saving throw or be pushed up to 10 feet away from you and knocked prone. If the affected creature is Large or larger, it has disadvantage on the saving throw.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sling</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="sling">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Sling</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Smash Potatoes" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SMASH_POTATOES">
		<description>
			<p>This hearty root vegetable is grown by the clerics and champions of a god of war and combat, whose strength is said to make its way onto the Material Plane through their gardens. Eating one of these vaguely fist-shaped potatoes will cause your hands to itch for the thrill of combat. Eating a potato increases your unarmed damage to 1d4 for 1 hour. Each additional eaten potato increases the duration by 1 hour. You can eat up to 3 potatoes before needing to finish a long rest to benefit from them again. If you already have an unarmed combat die that is 1d4 or higher, this vegetable has no effect but is nevertheless delicious.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Snuff" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SNUFF">
		<description>
			<p>This dark metal sickle was forged with an unusually harsh angle and has a unique power over light and shadow. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. You can speak the sickle's command word as an action to dispel magical lights and extinguish nonmagical flames within 60 feet of you. Magical lights dispelled in this way are affected as if they were targeted by the <i>dispel magic</i> spell. Once this property of the sickle has been used, it can't be used again until the next dusk.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action, you can draw your hand over the sickle's handle to magically extend it downward: turning the sickle into the form of a scythe wreathed in shadow. While in this form, the sickle has the two-handed and reach properties. While holding the weapon, you can return the sickle to its one-handed form using a bonus action.</p>
			<p class="indent">This weapon is particularly lethal to creatures. Creatures hit by this weapon take an extra 1d6 psychic damage. This bonus increases to 2d6 if the weapon is transformed into the scythe.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sickle</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="sickle">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Sickle</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Snugglebeast (owlbear)" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SNUGGLEBEAST_OWLBEAR">
		<description>
			<p>When a creature regains hit points at the end of a short rest by spending one or more of its Hit Dice, that creature can regain extra 1d6 hit points if it spends that short rest snuggling with one of these enchanted toys. Once this property of the <i>snugglebeast</i> has been used by a creature, that creature can't benefit from the same <i>snugglebeast</i> again in this way until it finishes a long rest.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Snugglebeast (unicorn)" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SNUGGLEBEAST_UNICORN">
		<description>
			<p>When a creature regains hit points at the end of a short rest by spending one or more of its Hit Dice, that creature can regain extra 2d6 hit points if it spends that short rest snuggling with one of these enchanted toys. Once this property of the <i>snugglebeast</i> has been used by a creature, that creature can't benefit from the same <i>snugglebeast</i> again in this way until it finishes a long rest.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Snugglebeast (dragon)" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SNUGGLEBEAST_DRAGON">
		<description>
			<p>When a creature regains hit points at the end of a short rest by spending one or more of its Hit Dice, that creature can regain extra 3d6 hit points if it spends that short rest snuggling with one of these enchanted toys. Once this property of the <i>snugglebeast</i> has been used by a creature, that creature can't benefit from the same <i>snugglebeast</i> again in this way until it finishes a long rest.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Snugglebeast (tarrasque)" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SNUGGLEBEAST_TARRASQUE">
		<description>
			<p>When a creature regains hit points at the end of a short rest by spending one or more of its Hit Dice, that creature can regain extra 4d6 hit points if it spends that short rest snuggling with one of these enchanted toys. Once this property of the <i>snugglebeast</i> has been used by a creature, that creature can't benefit from the same <i>snugglebeast</i> again in this way until it finishes a long rest.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Socks of the Well-Rested" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SOCKS_OFTHE_WELLRESTED">
		<description>
			<p>Wearing these comfortable enchanted socks allows you to recover an additional Hit Die (up to your maximum) upon finishing a long rest. You must be wearing both socks on your feet in order to gain this benefit. You can only benefit from wearing one pair of these socks at a time.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">feet</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Spellwoven Robes" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SPELLWOVEN_ROBES">
		<description>
			<p>These robes are spun from special, magic-sensitive threads, causing arcane glyphs to appear on the robe while you wear it whenever you cast a spell. While wearing these robes and no other armor, your AC is equal to 10 + your spellcasting ability modifier. In addition, whenever you cast a spell of 1st level or higher, you can change the apparent style, color, and apparent material of the robe. Regardless of its appearance, it is always a robe and its weight remains the same.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Spellwoven Robes - Spellcasting Ability" supports="Spellwoven Robes" />
			<stat name="ac:spellwoven robes" value="10" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:spellwoven robes" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none],[shield:none]" alt="Spellwoven Robes" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<!-- -->
	<element name="Spellwoven Robes - Intelligence" type="Class Feature" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_CLASS_FEATURE_SPELLWOVEN_ROBES_INT">
		<supports>Spellwoven Robes</supports>
		<description />
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:spellwoven robes" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="spellcasting ability" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Spellwoven Robes - Wisdom" type="Class Feature" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_CLASS_FEATURE_SPELLWOVEN_ROBES_WIS">
		<supports>Spellwoven Robes</supports>
		<description />
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:spellwoven robes" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="spellcasting ability" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Spellwoven Robes - Charisma" type="Class Feature" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_CLASS_FEATURE_SPELLWOVEN_ROBES_CHA">
		<supports>Spellwoven Robes</supports>
		<description />
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:spellwoven robes" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="spellcasting ability" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<!-- -->
	<element name="Spiderbite Daggers" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SPIDERBITE_DAGGERS">
		<description>
			<p>This pair of daggers is made using the harvested fangs of a large, venomous spider. When you hit the same creature on your turn with both daggers, that creature must succeed on a DC 13 Constitution saving throw or take an extra 2d4 poison damage and become poisoned until the end of its next turn.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">dagger</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="daggers">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Dagger</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Spire Seed" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SPIRE_SEED">
		<description>
			<p>This large tree seed is 1 foot long and surrounded by a protective cone. If you're attuned to the seed and plant it and its cone in soil, it immediately takes root and begins to grow rapidly. It takes 1 month for the seed to fully grow. If you are dead for longer than 1 minute or are on a different plane of existence than the seed for more than 1 day while it grows, the tree dies and the seed is destroyed.</p>
			<p class="indent">The stem of the seed's cone is vaguely key-shaped. When planted, the stem breaks off in your hand. While you're attuned to the seed, the stem magically remains on your person at all times.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once fully grown, the <i>spire tree</i> is 300 feet tall with a 20-foot radius. It tapers gently inward towards the top of the tree. At the base of this magic tree is a door large enough for Medium creatures to enter. The door is guarded by a dryad who is loyal to you and any creature you choose. The dryad accepts the seed's stem as proof of ownership and uses it as a key to open the door. Once opened, your attunement to the seed ends, the tree belongs to you, and both you and other allies you designate to the dryad can enter and leave the tree at will. Your attunement to the seed does not end if you are more than 100 feet away from it, and can only be ended early by a wish spell. If it does, the key disintegrates and the door cannot be opened.</p>
			<p class="indent">Inside the tree are 10 floors. You choose how to distribute the floors throughout the tree. A wooden spiral staircase climbs upward through the center of the tree and floors. Each floor has 10 small windows that can't be seen from outside the tree. In addition, the interior of the tree can't be the target of divination magic or entered by teleportation or by extradimensional or interplanar means.</p>
			<p class="indent">The canopy of the tree extends 30 feet beyond the base of the tree. Soil beneath the tree's canopy is exceptionally rich and fertile.</p>
			<p class="indent">The tree has 500 hit points, immunity to damage from nonmagical weapons that aren't siege weapons, and resistance to siege weapons and all other damage. The door has 100 hit points. The tree regains 1d6 lost hit points every day after taking damage. If a part of the tree, such as the door, is destroyed, a new one regrows after 7 days.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the tree is attacked, it immediately creates a treant at its base to defend it. Roll initiative for the treant, which has its own turns and does its best to defend the tree. Once a treant is created in this way, a new one can't be created until the next dawn. A treant disappears after 24 hours, and there can only be one summoned treant at a time. Neither the treant nor the dryad can move farther than 1 mile from the tree. If the dryad is slain, it reappears the following dawn at the base of the tree. If you kill the dryad, the tree becomes a nonmagical tree that is still hollow inside with the floors you'd chosen, but its windows are lost</p>
			<p class="indent">The tree creates another <i>spire seed</i> once every 100 years.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Spirit Pike" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SPIRIT_PIKE">
		<description>
			<p>If you're not proficient with pikes, you are nevertheless proficient with the <i>spirit pike</i> while you're attuned to it. When you cast the <i>spiritual weapon</i> spell, you can dissolve this weapon into the air and command the spell's spectral weapon to take the form of the <i>spirit pike</i>. Your spell attacks with this spectral weapon deal force damage equal to 1d10 + your spellcasting modifier instead of its normal damage. The spell's damage still increases by 1d8 for every two slot levels you use to cast the spell above 2nd.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your hands are left free while the pike is dissolved in this way. When the spell ends, the pike reappears in your hands or appears on the ground at your feet if your hands are full.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, the weapon has 4 charges and regains all of them each day at dawn. When you hit a target with a weapon or spell attack using the pike as either a physical or spectral weapon, you can expend 1 charge to deal 1d8 radiant damage to the target in addition to the attack's damage.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">pike</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="pike">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a cleric">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Pike</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_PIKE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Splintershot" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SPLINTERSHOT">
		<description>
			<p>This shortbow can cause an arrow to shatter and unleash a devastating spray of magical shrapnel. You can say the weapon's command word as an action to destroy 1 nonmagical arrow and send splintering shards of arcane energy out in front of you. When you do, creatures within a 15-foot cone must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, an affected creature takes 2d6 magical piercing damage, or 3d6 if the creature was within 5 feet of you.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shortbow</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shortbow">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Shortbow</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Splitter" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SPLITTER">
		<description>
			<p>This halberd's haft is made of rough, dark wood and is miraculously easy to heft. The bladed end of the halberd looks like a hatchet that's been absorbed by the hewn wood. While holding the halberd with two hands, you can speak its command word as a bonus action to split the weapon into its more basic components. When you do, the halberd deconstructs in your hands, leaving you with a handaxe in one hand and quarterstaff in the other. Both the handaxe and quarterstaff have the light property. You can combine the two weapons to reform the halberd by speaking its command word again as a bonus action while you're holding both the handaxe and quarterstaff.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. If the weapon is split into the handaxe and quarterstaff, the bonus is +1 with each weapon instead.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Halberd.</i></b> If you're wielding the halberd and roll a 10 on the damage die for an attack against a creature, that creature's energy is sapped. The creature's speed is reduced by 10 feet until the end of its next turn, and your speed is increased by 10 feet until the end of your turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Handaxe and Quarterstaff.</i></b> If you're wielding the handaxe and quarterstaff in either hand, you gain a +1 bonus to AC and can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack when you engage in two-weapon fighting. The quarterstaff deals necrotic damage, and its damage die is maximized if it hits a nonmagical plant or plant creature. If you make a ranged attack with the handaxe, it flies back to your hand immediately after the attack.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">halberd</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="type" addition="halberd">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Halberd</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Squasher" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SQUASHER">
		<description>
			<p>This enormous squash is strangely durable and makes for a functional magic weapon. Druids wielding <i>squasher</i> are proficient with the weapon and can use their Wisdom modifier for the weapon's attack and damage rolls instead of Strength.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">greatclub</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greatclub">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greatclub</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Staff of Favorable Winds" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_STAFF_OFTHE_FAVORABLE_WINDS">
		<description>
			<p>While you hold this staff, areas affected by strong winds do not count as difficult terrain for you.</p>
			<p class="indent">The staff has 10 charges. While holding it, you can expend 1 or more of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it using the required casting time as well as your spell save DC: <i>cone of cold</i> (5 charges), <i>feather fall</i> (1 charge), <i>gust of wind</i> (2 charges), or <i>wind wall</i> (3 charges).</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, while holding the staff, you can create a harmless sensory effect using the air. You can cause leaves to rustle, slam shutters closed in a sudden gust, or cause your clothing to billow dramatically.</p>
			<p class="indent">The staff regains 1d6 + 4 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the staff turns to dust and is blown away by a sudden flurry of wind.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition=" by a druid, sorcerer, warlock, or wizard">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Staff of the Four Seasons" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_STAFF_OFTHE_FOUR_SEASONS">
		<description>
			<p>This magical staff changes with the seasons. You can spend 10 minutes concentrating on the staff to change it to a different season. It remains in this new form for the next 8 hours before reverting to the current season again.</p>
			<p class="indent">This staff can be wielded as a magic quarterstaff that grants a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. In addition, your melee attacks with the staff deal an extra 1d8 cold (Winter), radiant (Spring), fire (Summer), or necrotic (Autumn) damage based on its season as long as there is at least 1 charge remaining on the staff.</p>
			<p class="indent">This staff has 10 charges. While holding the staff, you can expend 1 or more of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it (depending on its season) using your spell attack modifier and spell save DC:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i></i>Winter.</b> <i>Color spray</i> (1 charge), <i>darkvision</i> (2 charges), <i>sleet storm</i> (3 charges)</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Spring.</i></b> <i>Guiding bolt</i> (1 charge), <i>moonbeam</i> (2 charges), <i>plant growth</i> (3 charges)</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Summer.</i></b> <i>Burning hands</i> (1 charge), <i>spike growth</i> (2 charges), <i>fireball</i> (3 charges)</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Autumn.</i></b> <i>Inflict wounds</i> (1 charge), <i>pass without trace</i> (2 charges), <i>vampiric touch</i> (3 charges)</p>
			<p class="indent">The staff regains 1d6 +2 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the staff loses all foliage and vitality, becoming a gnarled, nonmagical quarterstaff.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition=" by a druid, sorcerer, warlock, or wizard">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Staff of the Magpie" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_STAFF_OFTHE_MAGPIE">
		<description>
			<p>This magic stone staff weighs 10 pounds and has the bust of a magpie at its top. While holding the staff, you gain a +1 bonus to Intelligence (Investigation) checks made to search for treasure or a specific item you're looking for.</p>
			<p class="indent">The staff has 10 charges. While holding the staff, you can use your action to cast one of the following spells from it: <i>fly</i> (3 charges) or <i>locate object</i> (2 charges). The staff regains 1d6 + 4 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the staff's last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the staff becomes a nonmagical quarterstaff as the magpie springs to life and flies away.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="10">10 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition=" by a spellcaster">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="investigation:misc" value="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Staff of the Mirage" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_STAFF_OFTHE_MIRAGE">
		<description>
			<p>This magical staff has 10 charges and regains 1d6 + 4 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the staff vanishes and is lost.</p>
			<p class="indent">Spells. You can use an action to expend 1 or more of the staff's charges to cast one of the following spells from it, using your spell save DC. You gain a +2 bonus to your spell save DC when casting one of these spells from the staff: <i>disguise self</i> (1 charge), <i>hallucinatory terrain</i> (4 charges), <i>invisibility</i> (2 charges), <i>mirror image</i> (2 charges), <i>mislead</i> (5 charges), or <i>silent image</i> (1 charge).</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition=" by a wizard">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Staff of the Mustang" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_STAFF_OFTHE_MUSTANG">
		<description>
			<p>This dark wooden staff is carved in the shape of a majestic stallion. The staff has 10 charges. While holding the staff, you can use an action to expend 1 of its charges to cast the phantom steed spell from it. Alternatively, while holding the staff, you can expend 1 of its charges and speak the staff's command word as a bonus action to take the Dash action.</p>
			<p class="indent">The staff regains 1d6 + 4 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the staff breaks in two as if bitten and is destroyed. When this happens, the sound of hooves can be heard galloping away in an indiscernible direction.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Staff of the Reverent Warrior" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_STAFF_OFTHE_REVERENT_WARRIOR">
		<description>
			<p>This staff was made as a means of worship rather than war by a retired warrior using the weapons he'd once wielded. The staff is adorned with blades and channels the inner focus of a warrior. This staff can be wielded as a magic quarterstaff that grants a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. In addition, attacks made with this weapon can deal either bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage (your choice).</p>
			<p class="indent">This staff has 10 charges. While attuned to the staff, you know the <i>true strike</i> cantrip and can cast it at will. When you cast this spell while holding the staff, you can expend 1 or more of its charges to enhance the spell in one or more of the following ways:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You can expend 1 charge to reveal the target's weaknesses to your allies instead of merely yourself, causing the next attack roll made against the target to have advantage instead.</li>
				<li>You can expend 1 charge to cast the spell as a bonus action, instead of as an action.</li>
				<li>You can expend 1 charge to cast the spell without it requiring concentration.</li>
				<li>You can expend 1 charge to cause the target to take an extra 2d6 damage from the next attack that hits it.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>The staff regains 1d6 + 4 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the staff becomes a nonmagical quarterstaff, but can still be used to deal either bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage with its attacks.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition=" by a spellcaster">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TRUE_STRIKE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Stalaga Spear" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_STALAGA_SPEAR">
		<description>
			<p>This magic spear is made of dark, polished granite and has a large ruby set in its head. While made of stone, it weighs no more than a normal spear and is enchanted to prevent it from shattering. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">The spear has 4 charges and regains 1d4 expended charges daily at dawn. While holding this spear in a space on or next to a surface made of unworked stone or earth, you can use an action and expend 1 of its charges to plunge the spear into that stone or earth surface. The spear vanishes into the surface and emerges as a sharp stone spike that is 1 foot wide and 10 feet long from another stone or earthen surface that you can see within 60 feet of you, such as the ground or a cave wall. The spike erupts from the surface and forces any creature within a line that is 5 feet wide and 10 feet long to make a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 4d6 piercing damage and is pushed up to 5 feet away from the spike. On a success, a creature takes half as much damage and isn't pushed.</p>
			<p class="indent">While you're within 60 feet of the stone spike and in a space on or next to a surface of unworked stone or earth, you can use a bonus action to speak the spear's command word to recall it. The stone spike crumbles and the spear inside vanishes back into the surface it came from before reemerging from the surface next to you into your open hand. If you don't have an open hand, it falls to the ground at your feet.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spear</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="type" addition="spear">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Spear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Starbreaker" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_STARBREAKER">
		<description>
			<p>This glowing morningstar casts bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet while you hold it. You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. Targets hit by the weapon take an extra 1d4 radiant damage. In addition, you can use an action to cast the <i>daylight</i> spell using the weapon. Once the weapon has been used to cast this spell, it can't do so again until the following dawn.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">morningstar</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="type" addition="morningstar">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Morningstar</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Starmetal Ring" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_STARMETAL_RING">
		<description>
			<p>This roughly crafted metal ring seems to have an otherworldly pull on other metallic items.</p>
			<p class="indent">While wearing the ring, you can spend 1 hour holding onto an object weighing no more than 25 pounds that is at least 50% metal. If the ring and metallic item are in contact for the full hour, they form a powerful and magically controllable magnetic bond. You can only have one item bound to the ring in this way at a time.</p>
			<p class="indent">While the bound item is within 40 feet from you and unobstructed, you can use a bonus action on your turn to magically pull it up to 20 feet toward you. The returning item bounces harmlessly against creatures and objects as it passes by.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Rings</set>
			<set name="slot">ring</set>
			<set name="type">Ring</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Starmetal Shield" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_STARMETAL_SHIELD">
		<description>
			<p>This open metal shield and gauntlet offer a +1 bonus to your armor class instead of a shield's normal bonus. Whenever you're the target of an attack made with a metal weapon or projectile, the bonus becomes +3 instead. The shield hovers above the gauntlet to protect you as if you were wielding it, leaving your hands free.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Shooting star.</i></b> As an action, you can throw the shield at up to 3 clustered targets you can see before returning to your arm. Choose up to 3 targets or points. The first target or point must be within 30 feet of you, and any additional targets or points must be within 10 feet of the one before it. You can't select the same target more than once.</p>
			<p class="indent">Make a ranged attack with the shield against each target. You are proficient with these attacks and add either your Dexterity or Strength modifier to its attack and damage rolls. Targets hit by the attack take 2d8 magical slashing damage. Once the shield reaches a target or point, it bounces towards the next target or point. The shield flies back to the gauntlet after reaching its final destination, bouncing harmlessly off of anything obstructing its path.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shield</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="attunement" >true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Starmetal Solar Axe" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_STARMETAL_SOLAR_AXE">
		<description>
			<p>This magic weapon is forged using iron from the stars. While you're attuned to this weapon, you can call upon its latent stellar energy to catalyze change within the metal and create endothermic and exothermic reactions. The weapon can be fused into a greataxe or fissioned into two separated battleaxes. The weapon has the following properties based on its current state:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Fused State.</i></b> While wielding the fused greataxe, you gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. While you hold this axe, flames erupt from its edges and a small star burns in its center. These flames shed bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. The light is sunlight. The greataxe deals an extra 2d6 fire damage to any target it hits.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Fissioned State.</i></b> While wielding the two fissioned battleaxes, you gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with them. The weapons are bitter cold to the touch and deal an extra 1d6 cold damage to any target they hit. The axes orbit you slowly while they aren't being held or stowed. You can retrieve a floating battleaxe as if it were sheathed. In addition, when you take the Attack action, you can use a bonus action to make one melee weapon attack with an orbiting battleaxe against a creature you can see within 20 feet of you.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>State Change.</i></b> This weapon can change between its two states using the following properties:</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Fission.</i></b> While holding the fused greataxe, you can use a bonus action to speak the weapon's command word to split it apart into its fissioned state. When you do, electrical energy is released, forcing creatures within 30 feet of you to make a DC 17 Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 3d6 lightning damage on a failed save, or half as much lightning damage on a successful one. This property can't be used again for 12 hours.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Fusion.</i></b> While holding both battleaxes, you can use a bonus action to speak the weapon's other command word to recombine the two battleaxes into its fused state. When you do, the sudden generation of heat creates a wave of fire around you, forcing creatures within 30 feet of you to make a DC 17 Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 3d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. This property can't be used again for 12 hours.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">greataxe</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="type" addition="greataxe">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">Greataxe</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Starmetal Striker" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_STARMETAL_STRIKER">
		<description>
			<p>This light hammer was forged using the remains of a comet and is cold to the touch. You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon, and when you hit with an attack using it, the target takes an extra 1d4 cold damage. The hammer leaves behind a crackling mist when thrown and immediately flies back to your hand after making a ranged attack with it.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">light hammer</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="type" addition="light hammer">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Light Hammer</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Steps of the Trickster" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_STEPS_OFTHE_TRICKSTER">
		<description>
			<p>These shoes allow you to freely change the sound of your steps when you wear them. Changing the sound of your steps doesn't change their volume, but can make them sound as though the shoes are made from a different material. For example, your steps can sound like a beggar's bare feet, a dancer's sharp heels, or an approaching guard's metal boots.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">feet</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Storm Sickle" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_STORM_SICKLE">
		<description>
			<p>This sickle sparks with electricity as beads of water form and drip from its blade. The weapon can make ranged attacks by slashing through the air to send out blades of storming wind. Ranged attacks with the sickle deal 1d4 slashing damage, use Strength as your modifier for its attack and damage rolls, and have a normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet. When you hit with an attack using this magic sickle, the target takes an extra 1d4 lightning damage.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sickle</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="sickle">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Sickle</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Stormstruck Staff" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_STORMSTRUCK_STAFF">
		<description>
			<p>This wooden staff has been scarred by lightning and embedded with an amplifying crystal at its head. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. Small sparks of electricity arc from the crystal, dealing an extra 1 lightning damage to any target hit by the weapon. The gem glows brilliantly and pulses with electrical energy for 1 minute after either the quarterstaff takes lightning damage or you take lightning damage while holding it from any source (other than itself ), or while the weapon is under the effects of the <i>shillelagh</i> spell. While the gem is glowing in this way, the extra lightning damage increases to 1d6, and the gem emits bright light out to 10 feet and dim light for an additional 10 feet.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Storm Thrower Harpoon" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_STORMTHOWER_HARPOON">
		<description>
			<p>This weapon has a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magical weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">The trident has a chain attached to its handle that can be used to retrieve the weapon once it's been thrown using a bonus action. When you hit with a ranged attack using this weapon, it deals an additional 1d8 lightning damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, this trident acts as a conduit for the sky's ferocious power. Immediately after hitting a creature with the trident, you can call down a bolt of lightning upon it, forcing it and all creatures within 5 feet to make a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, creatures take 6d10 lightning damage, or half as much on a success. Creatures have disadvantage on the saving throw if they're submerged in water or wearing metal armor. You are immune to the lightning damage caused by this effect. This ability fails if the creatures are obstructed from the sky. Once you use this ability, you cannot do so again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Impale.</i></b> You can use your action to try to impale and pull a creature toward you. If your target is a creature that is no more than one size larger than you, you can make a ranged weapon attack against it using the trident. If you hit, you can attempt to pull the impaled creature toward you by making a Strength (Athletics) check contested by the target's Strength (Athletics) check. If you succeed, you can pull the creature up to 20 feet toward you.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">trident</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="type" addition="trident">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">Trident</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sundersludge Net" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SUNDERSLUDGE_NET">
		<description>
			<p>This gelatinous net is made with the enchanted remains of a gray ooze. A creature takes 1d6 acid damage when it's restrained by the net and again at the end of each of its turns while it remains restrained by it. If the creature is wearing nonmagical metal armor, its armor is partly corroded and takes a permanent and cumulative -1 penalty to the AC it offers whenever it takes acid damage at the end of one of its turns. The armor is destroyed if the penalty reduces its AC to 10. A creature other than you who touches the net takes 1d6 acid damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">The net's sticky composition makes it more difficult to escape than a mundane one. A creature can use its action to make a DC 13 Strength check, freeing itself or another creature within its reach on a success. The net has resistance to all damage types. Dealing 10 slashing damage to the net (AC 12) also frees the creature without harming it, ending the effect and tearing the net apart.</p>
			<p class="indent">The torn net is harmless. If more than half of the net can be salvaged and stored within a container large enough to hold 1 gallon of liquid for 12 hours, the net is repaired and can be used once more. Your attunement to the net ends if the net remains destroyed for longer than 2 days.</p>
			<p class="indent">You're immune to damage from the net while you're attuned to it. Picking up the net after throwing it renders it harmless until the next time you throw it. The net deals no acid damage if no creature is attuned to it.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">net</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="type" addition="net">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Net</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Switch" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SWITCH">
		<description>
			<p>This simple, springy rod is made of twisting vines and twigs. While attuned to the rod, you can expend 1 use of your wild shape feature as a bonus action to activate it. The rod stays active for a number of hours equal to half your druid level (rounded down).</p>
			<p class="indent">When you activate the rod and again on subsequent turns as a bonus action while the rod is active, you can transform the rod into a bludgeoning or piercing weapon of your choice that has neither the loading nor reach property. You're proficient with this weapon and can use Wisdom as your modifier for its attack and damage rolls instead of Dexterity or Strength. A weapon that uses ammunition magically creates its own. Alternatively, you can transform <i>switch</i> back into its rod form if you so choose. Regardless of the weapon you make, targets hit by it take an extra 1d8 damage of the weapon's type. If the weapon you create has the light property, you can make a weapon attack with it using a bonus action.</p>
			<p class="indent">While the rod is activated, you can use an action to expend a second use of your wild shape feature and extend the rod's barked exterior to your body. This tree-like armor can take on any form that you choose. You gain temporary hit points equal to 4 times your Druid level, and your armor class can't be lower than 16 while the rod is active. Using this property of the activated rod does not extend its remaining duration.</p>
			<p class="indent"><i>Switch</i> becomes inactive at the end of its duration, you fall to 0 hit points, or end it early as a bonus action. When it's inactive, it reverts to its normal rod form.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Rods</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Rod</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition=" by a druid">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sword of Resonance" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SWORD_OF_RESONANCE">
		<description>
			<p>This peculiar brass longsword is hollow and has lute strings that run along its blade, allowing you to use this sword as both a lute and spellcasting focus. You're proficient with this lute while you're attuned to the sword. This sword also has the finesse property due to the hollow blade's reduced weight.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. In addition, the sword's hollow metal blade magically amplifies the music made when using it to inspire allies. Whenever you expend a use of your Bardic Inspiration, the sword begins to reverberate with thunderous energy. The next time you hit a target before the end of your next turn with an attack using the sword, that target takes an extra 1d6 thunder damage from the attack.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">longsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition=" by a bard">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sword of the Spelldrinker" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_SWORD_OFTHE_SPELLDRINKER">
		<description>
			<p>This sword seems to absorb any light that touches it, making it appear darker than the deepest midnight. You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. While you hold this sword, you treat any magical light, darkness, or atmospheric effect within 30 feet of you as if it were nonmagical and breathable.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, this sword has 2 charges and regains 1d2 expended charges daily at dusk. While holding the sword, you can expend 1 of its charges to cast the <i>counterspell</i> spell (5th-level version) from it. If you successfully interrupt a spell in this way, you can choose to absorb it into the sword instead of countering it. If the triggering spell was cast at 6th level or higher, your <i>counterspell</i> automatically fails. The absorbed spell must have a casting time of one action or bonus action. The sword can have only one absorbed spell at a time.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use an action while holding the sword to release an absorbed spell. When you do, the spell uses the slot level, spell save DC, spell attack bonus, and spellcasting ability of the original caster, but is otherwise treated as if you cast the spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">The interrupted spell remains absorbed by the sword for up to 8 hours or until released. Absorbing a new spell replaces the one stored within the sword.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">longsword</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">Halberd</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
</elements>
