<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Book 1: Magic Items C</name>
		<description>The first published work</description>                             
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="book-1-items-c.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tel0k/Aurora-Builder-Griffon-s-Saddlebag/main/elements/Griffon-s-Book-1/book-1-items-c.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Cactus Mace" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CACTUS_MACE" >
		<description>
			<p>This magical weapon's head is an enchanted cactus that rapidly regrows its missing needles. The first target hit by this weapon on each of your turns takes an extra 1d4 piercing damage from the attack.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">mace</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="mace">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Candle of Anti-light" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CANDLE_OF_ANTILIGHT" >
		<description>
			<p>While burning, this dark candle sheds magical darkness in a 10-foot radius. It can be lit for up to 1 hour before it's consumed and can be snuffed or relit like a normal candle as a bonus action. Completely covering the candle with something opaque contains the darkness. A creature with darkvision can't see through this darkness, and nonmagical light can't illuminate it.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Catnip Amulet" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CATNIP_AMULET" >
		<description>
			<p>This gold and jade amulet seems to draw domestic cats to it. While wearing the necklace, you have advantage on ability checks made to find or call Tiny domestic cats (if there are any) and on Wisdom (Animal Handling) checks you make to interact with them.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Celestial Circlet" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CELESTIAL_CIRCLET" >
		<description>
			<p>This golden circlet radiates holy energy. A thin halo hovers above your head while you wear it, emitting bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for another 20 feet. Small motes of holy light swirl around the apex of the circlet.</p>
			<p class="indent">While you wear the circlet, you are always under the effects of the <i>protection from evil and good</i> spell. This effect only applies to one creature type: you can choose a new creature type (other than celestials) to be protected against daily at dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent">The circlet has 7 charges. As an action while wearing the circlet, you can expend 1 or more of its charges to cast either <i>cure wounds</i> (1 charge per spell level, up to 4th) or <i>spirit guardians</i> (3 charges) from it, using your spell save DC and spellcasting ability modifier. Immediately before or after you cast a spell from the circlet in this way, you can use your bonus action to fly up to 10 feet without provoking opportunity attacks. When you do, you are carried away on a pair of angelic wings.</p>
			<p class="indent">The circlet regains 1d4 + 3 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the halo vanishes and the circlet becomes mundane and nonmagical.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">circlet</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a cleric of good alignment">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ceratopper" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CERATOPPER" >
		<description>
			<p>This adamantine helm is fashioned in the likeness of a triceratops and decorated with painted designs. You have a +1 bonus to AC while you wear this helmet. If you move at least 20 feet toward a target and then attack it with a melee weapon attack on the same turn, you can choose to make a special attack using the helmet instead of the weapon. On a hit, the target takes piercing damage equal to 3d4 + your Strength modifier. You're proficient with this attack and use your Strength modifier for its attack rolls. If you hit and the target is no more than one size larger than you, it must also succeed on a DC 13 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, while wearing the helmet, you can use an action to cast the <i>polymorph</i> spell from it, transforming yourself into a triceratops. Once this property has been used, it can't be used again until 2 days have passed.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:misc" value="1" />
		</rules>
		</element>
	<element name="Charlatan's Wardrobe" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CHARLATANS_WARDROBE" >
		<description>
			<p>This set of plain clothes is exceptionally comfortable and easy to wear. They are always clean and smell freshly washed and lightly perfumed. You can change the appearance of the outfit as an action by twirling in place and speaking the clothes' command word. The outfit's appearance is illusory. Physical interaction with the clothes reveals their appearance to be an illusion, because things can pass through it. A creature that uses its action to examine the clothes can determine that it is an illusion with a successful DC 13 Intelligence (Investigation) check. Regardless of their appearance, the clothes offer no additional protection from the elements, and can only appear to be clothes.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Chillspike" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CHILLSPIKE" >
		<description>
			<p>This cold steel weapon from the Everglacier is topped with a menacing ice spike that never melts. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. The pike deals an extra 1d10 cold damage to any target it hits. In addition, attacks with this weapon and its properties ignore resistance to cold damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you reduce a Large or smaller creature to 0 hit points using this weapon, you can choose to encase that creature in ice. An encased creature is prevented from falling prone and is held in place by a shell of ice for 1 minute. If the creature is unconscious, it does not make death saving throws while it's encased in the ice. The ice has AC 12, 20 hit points, immunity to poison and psychic damage, and vulnerability to fire damage. If the encased creature is healed or the ice is destroyed, the ice crumbles and releases the creature.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Everglacier's Fury.</i></b> As an action, you can plunge the pike into the ground at your feet. When you do, the blade of the pike magically vanishes into the earth and summons up to three icy spikes from the ground nearby. Choose up to 3 different targets on the ground you can see within 20 feet of you. An affected target must succeed on a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw or take 2d8 cold damage as a frozen spike erupts from the ground beneath it. The spikes immediately recede into the ground after the effect, and the icy blade of the pike reappears.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">pike</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="pike">Weapon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Chromacloth" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CHRONOMACLOTH" >
		<description>
			<p>This silken cloth is enchanted using a unique blend of abjuration and evocation magic, allowing it to be used for a number of purposes. At any one time it can be one of four colors: red, yellow, green, or blue. You can change the chromacloth's color to another one as an action.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can wear the chromacloth as a headband or wrap to gain resistance to the damage type associated with the cloth's color. Once the cloth reduces damage taken in this way, it can't do so again until the following dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent">Alternatively, the cloth can be fashioned to be an effective sling. Ammunition fired from the sling deals damage of a type matching the cloth's color instead of bludgeoning.</p>
			<p class="indent">Refer to the table below for a reference of the chromacloth's associated colors and damage types:</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Color</td><td>Damage type</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Red</td><td>Fire</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Yellow</td><td>Lightning</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Green</td><td>Poison</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Blue</td><td>Cold</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">sling</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="sling">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Cinnabar Rapier" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CINNABAR_RAPIER" >
		<description>
			<p>This magic rapier's blade is alchemically coated in a thin but toxic layer of cinnabar. The weapon has 10 charges and regains 1d8+2 expended charges each day at dawn. When you hit a creature with this weapon, you can expend 1 or more of its charges. The blade's poison leeches into the blood of the creature you struck to deal an extra 1d4 poison damage for each charge expended in this way.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">rapier</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="type" addition="rapier">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Circlet of the Huntsman's Third Eye" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CIRCLET_OF_THE_HUNTSMANS_THIRD_EYE" >
		<description>
			<p>This barbed metal circlet features a grotesque yet ornately preserved eye hanging from its center. The eye rests on the forehead of the creature wearing it. While wearing the circlet, its latent cunning guides your hand, giving you advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks.</p>
			<p class="indent">The circlet has 5 charges and regains all expended charges daily at dusk. While wearing the circlet, you can use a bonus action to expend 1 of its charges to cast the <i>hunter's mark</i> spell from it. You have advantage on Constitution saving throws made to maintain concentration on this spell. In addition, you can expend a 2nd charge when casting <i>hunter's mark</i> in this way, or 1 charge as a bonus action on another turn, to gain truesight out to a range of 120 feet for 1 minute.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Curse.</i></b> Attuning to the circlet curses you until you are targeted by the <i>remove curse</i> spell or similar magic. Removing the circlet fails to end the curse. While cursed, whenever you roll a 1 on an attack roll or ability check, you take 1d6 psychic damage as the eye's intense frustration and scorn pierce your psyche.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Cloak of the Boundless Spirit" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CLOAK_OF_THE_BOUNDLESS_SPIRIT" >
		<description>
			<p>This swirling, translucent cloak bolsters the fighting spirits of friendly nearby creatures. The cloak has 3 charges and regains all expended charges each day at dawn. When an ally you can see within 15 feet of you takes damage, you can use your reaction to expend 1 charge and reduce that damage by 2d6.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, friendly creatures within 15 feet of you regain consciousness on a roll of 19 or 20 on death saving throws. When a creature within range regains consciousness in this way, you can use a reaction to expend 1 charge to grant them 2d6 temporary hit points. Once a creature regains consciousness by rolling a 19 on a death saving throw in this way, it can't do so again until it finishes a long rest.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">shoulders</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Clockwork Faefly" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CLOCKWORK_FAEFLY" >
		<description>
			<p>This brass clockwork mechanism is 2 inches long and whirs with the hum of tiny gears inside. You can tap the head of the faefly twice as a bonus action. When you do, the mechanism begins to flutter 5 feet in the air. The faefly has AC 10 and 10 hit points and flies in this way until a creature grasps it or it falls to 0 hit points. If you move more than 60 feet from the hovering faefly, it follows you until it is within 60 feet of you. It takes the shortest route to do so. If prevented from moving, the faefly sinks gently to the ground and becomes inactive, and its light fades out. While it's flying, you can use a bonus action to speak its command word to cause it to move up to 20 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you are within 60 feet of the faefly, you can speak another command word as an action to cause it to emit the <i>light</i> spell or cast <i>faerie fire</i> (save DC 13), affecting a 20-foot cube originating from itself. <i>Faerie fire</i> does not require concentration when cast in this way, but ends early if the faefly falls to 0 hit points. Once the faefly casts the <i>faerie fire</i> spell, it can't cast it again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent">The faefly is considered a magical object and is not a creature. If the <i>mending</i> spell is cast on it while it has at least 1 hit point, it regains 2d6 hit points. If the faefly falls to 0 hit points, it can't be used again until 2 days have passed, at which point it regains all its hit points.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Clockwork Healerbee" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CLOCKWORK_HEALERBEE" >
		<description>
			<p>This pill-shaped magical mechanism is 2 inches long and made of brass and glass. It has a pair of tiny wings that silently keep it aloft. It hovers up to 5 feet above the ground and does its best to stay at your side within your space. The bee can enter and pass through another creature's space and does not provoke opportunity attacks.</p>
			<p class="indent">The bee has 8 charges and regains 1d6 + 2 expended charges daily at dawn. While the bee is within your space, you can speak its command word as a bonus action and expend up to 3 of its charges to command the bee to heal a creature that you can see within 20 feet of you. The bee flies to the creature's space and touches its stinger to the creature, causing the creature to regain 1d6 hit points for each expended charge and emitting a bright light that fills the space. After healing the creature, the bee returns to your space.</p>
			<p class="indent">The bee is considered a magical object and is not a creature. It has AC 15, 10 hit points, and has resistance to all damage. If the <i>mending</i> spell is cast on the bee while it has at least 1 hit point, it regains 2d6 hit points. If the bee drops to 0 hit points, it can't be used again for 24 hours, at which point it regains all its hit points.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Clockwork Inkbeetle" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CLOCKWORK_INKBEETLE" >
		<description>
			<p>This minuscule, mechanical beetle is 1 inch long and quietly whirs with a mix of magical and mechanical forces. Placing the beetle on a piece of parchment you hold or carry causes it to spring to life and begin tracking your travels. As you move, so does the beetle: leaving behind a small line of ink. The ink immediately dries and doesn't dissolve in water. In addition, the beetle's small frame allows it to move even while enclosed in a book or similar enclosure without losing its sense of movement or direction.</p>
			<p class="indent">The beetle mirrors your movement to create a to-scale map of your journey, drawing 1 inch of ink in your choice of the following scales: 20 feet/inch, 200 feet/inch, 2 miles/inch, or 20 miles/inch. You can rotate the dial on the beetle's underside to change the scale as an action. The beetle is immune to magical effects that would otherwise alter its sense of direction.</p>
			<p class="indent">The beetle always knows which direction is north. When placed on a piece of parchment for the first time, it crouches down to stamp a small compass rose on the sheet before it begins to move. If the beetle runs out of space on the parchment to travel, it stops moving in that direction and emits a clicking sound that can be heard by creatures within 5 feet of it.</p>
			<p class="indent">Attaching one <i>band of the found and lost</i> to the beetle while you wear the other allows the beetle to move and trace your movements in this way from afar so long as you are both on the same plane of existence.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Coil Crook" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_COIL_CROOK" >
		<description>
			<p>This smooth red staff is actually made from a rigid length of rope. You can speak the staff 's command word as a bonus action to cause it to magically loosen and turn into a 10-foot length of decorative silken rope. You can speak the staff 's command word again as a bonus action to cause the rope to untangle itself and become the solid staff form once more. It can be used as a spellcasting focus in either of these forms.</p>
			<p class="indent">While holding the staff, you can use an action to cast the <i>rope trick</i> spell from it, using it as the rope required for the spell. Once this property has been used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Coldsnap" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_COLDSNAP" >
		<description>
			<p>This icy whip deals an extra 1d4 cold damage to any target it hits. In addition, you have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">The whip has 3 charges and regains all of them each day at dawn. When you hit a creature that is not immune to cold damage with this weapon, you can expend 1 of its charges to force the creature to make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw. On a failure, its speed becomes 0 until the start of your next turn. On a success, its speed is halved instead.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you attune to this weapon, its normally frigid handle feels warm to the touch.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">whip</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="whip">Weapon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Whip</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Companion's Band" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_COMPANIONS_BAND" >
		<description>
			<p>This woven band can be worn as a necklace or bracelet by resizing its strap. While wearing the band, you can use an action to summon a spectral companion that appears in a space within 5 feet of you. The companion can be a dog, cat, bird, or similar Small or smaller beast. The form is translucent and immaterial, but feels warm to the touch. It emits dim light in a 5-foot radius. The companion remains until dismissed (no action required) or until you remove the band. It is not considered to be a creature, does not occupy space, and does not require food, water, or air to exist. It is friendly toward you and other creatures you choose. It stays within 30 feet of you at all times and moves through objects as necessary in order to do so. If it's unable to reach you, it disappears until summoned again. The companion wears a spectral copy of the band on its neck or limb when you summon it (your choice).</p>
			<p class="indent">The companion understands the emotion and intent of your commands, but cannot speak or understand language. Attempting to target the companion with a detect thoughts spell only reveals an overwhelming sense of love and affection for you.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once the same spectral companion has remained or has been summoned at least once a day for 7 consecutive days, the band and companion become permanently linked to you. When this happens, the band no longer requires you be attuned to it in order to use it, and no other creature can attune to it. Once the band is linked to you in this way, you can summon your linked companion using a bonus action instead of an action. In addition, once the band is linked to you, the companion becomes partially physical, allowing you and creatures you choose to be able to gently pet and hold its otherwise spectral form.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you die, the band can be attuned to by a different creature. The linked companion follows you to whatever afterlife awaits you or reappears if you're resurrected and summon it once again.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Container of Heat and Frost" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CONTAINER_OF_HEAT_AND_FROST">
		<description>
			<p>This heavy iron container is adorned with 3 arcane symbols along the edge of its removable lid. The container can hold up to 1 gallon of liquid. As an action, you can press 1 of the container's arcane glyphs to heat the liquid inside to a boil (212 degrees Fahrenheit), chill it (33 degrees Fahrenheit), or maintain its current temperature (keeping it between 33 and 212 degrees Fahrenheit). Once pressed, the selected glyph glows either red, blue, or yellow, respectively.</p>
			<p class="indent">It takes 1 minute to boil or chill a liquid. Pressing the glyph again as an action ends the heating or cooling process early. After boiling or chilling the liquid, the container maintains its hot or cool temperature, respectively.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Coralshield Golem" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CORALSHIELD_GOLEM" >
		<description>
			<p>This crablike golem is made of a light but resilient magical coral. While wearing it on your back, you can use a bonus action to command it to move along your arm and don itself. You can command the golem to return to your back using another bonus action.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you don't have a free hand or refuse to drop what you're holding when the golem attempts to don itself, it returns and reattaches to your back.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shield</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
			<set name="attunement" >true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Couatl Herald's Fang" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_COUALT_HERALDS_FANG" >
		<description>
			<p>This vibrant blade carries with it some of the properties of the couatl who either forged it or the couatl whose scales it was crafted from. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. In addition, when you roll a 20 on an attack roll made with this weapon, the target takes an extra 2d6 poison damage and must make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw. On a failure, the target is incapacitated and has a speed of 0 until it takes any damage or someone else uses an action to shake the target out of its stupor.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Flight of the Couatls.</i></b> While you're attuned to 3 items with this property, you gain a flying speed of 30 feet. If you already have a flying speed, your flying speed increases by 30 feet instead.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any sword or dagger">Weapon</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_SWORDS||Dagger</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a  creature of good alignment">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Couatl Herald's Guard" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_COUALT_HERALDS_GUARD" >
		<description>
			<p>This magic shield is made from yew and covered in durable couatl feathers. When a creature you can see within 10 feet of you takes damage, you can use your reaction to magically take that damage instead of the creature taking it. When you do so, the damage type changes to force. Once this property has been used, it can't be used again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Flight of the Couatls.</i></b> While you're attuned to 3 items with this property, you gain a flying speed of 30 feet. If you already have a flying speed, your flying speed increases by 30 feet instead.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a  creature of good alignment">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Couatl Herald's Lash" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_COUALT_HERALDS_LASH" >
		<description>
			<p>This slender whip's grip is feathered and comfortable to wield. Its weight has been magically reduced and it gently sways on its own. This weapon has the light property. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once on each of your turns when you take the Attack action and use this whip to make an attack against a Medium or smaller creature, you can choose to forgo the attack and force the target to make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw instead. On a failure, the target is grappled by the whip and takes 1d4 bludgeoning damage as it's constricted. If you replace another attack with the whip in this way against a target who's already grappled by it, that target becomes restrained by the whip instead upon failing the saving throw.</p>
			<p class="indent">A target grappled or restrained by the whip can use an action to make a DC 15 Strength or Dexterity check (target's choice). On a success, it is no longer grappled or restrained by the whip.</p>
			<p class="indent">Until this grapple or restraint ends, you can't use the whip against a different target. Moving more than 10 feet away from the target or dropping the whip ends the grapple or restraint.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Flight of the Couatls.</i></b> While you're attuned to 3 items with this property, you gain a flying speed of 30 feet. If you already have a flying speed, your flying speed increases by 30 feet instead.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="whip">Weapon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Whip</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a  creature of good alignment">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Couatl Herald's Mantle" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_COUALT_HERALDS_MANTLE" >
		<description>
			<p>This magic cloak is given to those deemed kind-hearted and responsible by a celestial. While wearing the mantle, you have advantage on saving throws to resist becoming poisoned or diseased. In addition, you are immune to any effect that would sense your emotions.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Flight of the Couatls.</i></b> While you're attuned to 3 items with this property, you gain a flying speed of 30 feet. If you already have a flying speed, your flying speed increases by 30 feet instead.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a  creature of good alignment">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Couatl Herald's Radiance" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_COUALT_HERALDS_RADIANCE" >
		<description>
			<p>This magic wooden staff was enchanted by a powerful couatl. The staff has 5 charges. While holding the staff, you can expend 1 of its charges to cast one of the following spells, using your spellcasting ability modifier and spell save DC: create food and water, cure wounds (2nd-level version), lesser restoration, protection from poison, sanctuary, or shield.</p>
			<p class="indent">The staff regains 1d3 + 2 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the staff vanishes in a flash of light, lost forever.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Flight of the Couatls.</i></b> While you're attuned to 3 items with this property, you gain a flying speed of 30 feet. If you already have a flying speed, your flying speed increases by 30 feet instead.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a  creature of good alignment">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Couatl Herald's Reach" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_COUALT_HERALDS_REACH" >
		<description>
			<p>This wooden bow is carved to resemble a mighty couatl. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. The bow has 4 charges and regains 1d3 + 1 expended charges daily at dawn. When you make a ranged attack against a Large or smaller creature with the bow, you can choose a limb to target and expend 1 of the bow's charges as part of the attack. If the attack hits, the weapon's damage becomes radiant, and the creature is forced to make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, that creature's targeted limb is pinned by radiant tethers of magic: holding it to its body or an adjacent surface (if any) for up to 1 minute.</p>
			<p class="indent">Depending on the pinned limb, the creature may fall over prone, be unable to move, or make weapon attacks with disadvantage while the limb remains pinned in this way. A creature can use its action to make a DC 15 Strength check, freeing itself or another creature within its reach on a success from the pinning tethers.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Flight of the Couatls.</i></b> While you're attuned to 3 items with this property, you gain a flying speed of 30 feet. If you already have a flying speed, your flying speed increases by 30 feet instead.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any bow">Weapon</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_BOWS</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a  creature of good alignment">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Couatl Herald's Scales" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_COUALT_HERALDS_SCALES" >
		<description>
			<p>This enchanted armor is made from couatl scales that were collected by a generous celestial. You gain a +1 bonus to AC while you wear this armor. This armor does not impose disadvantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Tooth and Scale.</i></b> When you take damage from a creature within 10 feet of you, you can use your reaction to channel the good spirit within the armor and cause a bright, spectral couatl to appear above you. The spectral form strikes at the creature who damaged you, forcing it to make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, the creature takes 4d10 radiant damage, or half as much damage on a success. Once this property has been used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Flight of the Couatls.</i></b> While you're attuned to 3 items with this property, you gain a flying speed of 30 feet. If you already have a flying speed, your flying speed increases by 30 feet instead.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="scale mail">Armor</set>
			<set name="armor">Scale Mail</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a  creature of good alignment">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Cratering Quarterstaf" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CRATERING_QUARTERSTAFF" >
		<description>
			<p>This thick, stony quarterstaff requires a Strength score of 17 or higher in order to wield. Despite glowing with embers, it feels comfortably warm to the touch. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">This quarterstaff has 5 charges and regains 1d4 + 1 expended charges daily at dawn. Once on each of your turns immediately after you make an attack with the quarterstaff, you can expend 1 of its charges (no action required) to slam the weapon into the ground and create a 10-foot cone of intense tremors and flame in the direction of the original attack's target. Any creature caught in the cone must make a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw. The original attack's target has disadvantage on the saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 1d8 bludgeoning damage and 1d8 fire damage, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="quarterstaff">Weapon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Crosier of Divine Power" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CROSIER_OF_DIVINE_POWER" >
		<description>
			<p>This staff can be wielded as a magic quarterstaff that grants a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it.</p>
			<p class="indent">This staff is enchanted with powerful holy magic that manifests as radiant motes of power during times of need. At the start of each of your turns in combat, roll a d6. On a 6, a mote of power appears above the head of the staff. When you hit a target with the staff or heal a creature with a spell or magical effect while holding it, you can expend 1 of these motes to add 2d6 to the total damage dealt or hit points healed. The extra damage is radiant.</p>
			<p class="indent">Each mote lasts for 1 minute or until it's expended. When you roll initiative against a hostile creature, the staff creates 2 motes.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a cleric or paladin">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Crown of Deep Winter" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CROWN_OF_DEEP_WINTER" >
		<description>
			<p>This icy crown is made using ice from the Everglacier. While wearing the crown, you have resistance to cold damage. In addition, you can use an action to cast the fire shield spell from it, making only a chill shield when you do. Once the crown has cast this spell, it can't cast it again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Frozen Burst.</i></b> While wearing this crown, you can use your reaction when a creature within 5 feet of you that you can see hits you with an attack to cause the area around you to explode in a burst of razor-sharp icicles. When you do, all creatures within 5 feet of you must make a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw. On a failure, a creature takes 2d8 cold damage, or half as much on a success. This property of the crown can't be used again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Crypt Keeper Glaive" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_CRYPT_KEEPER_GLAIVE" >
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you use the glaive to reduce a Small or larger creature that is hostile toward you to 0 hit points, roll a d10. You gain temporary hit points equal to the number you roll.</p>
		</description>	
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">glaive</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="glaive">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

</elements>