<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name></name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="book-1-artifacts.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Tel0k/Aurora-Builder-Griffon-s-Saddlebag/main/elements/Griffon-s-Saddlebag/Griffon-s-Book-1/book-1-artifacts.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Galea of the Soulfire Phoenix" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_GALEA_OFTHE_SOULFIRE_PHOENIX">
		<description>
			<p>TThis magical helmet once belonged to the Soulfire Phoenix Fara, a paragon to the citizens of the Elemental Plane of Fire who led her people to victory during the Savrayan Wars. While some believe that her ferocity and heroism were a result of phoenix blood running through her veins, others claim that a hero will always rise from the ashes when the time is right.</p>
			<p class="indent">A spark of this heroism resides within the helmet, imparting its passion and phoenix-like properties to you. While wearing the helmet, you have resistance to fire damage, and while you're in combat, magical flames erupt from it. The fire is harmless and casts bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Fiery Spirit.</i></b> While wearing the helmet, you and friendly creatures standing within its bright light have advantage on saving throws against becoming charmed or frightened. In addition, you and friendly creatures within the bright light regain 1 hit point on a roll of 19 or 20 on death saving throws.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Ignite.</i></b> While wearing the helmet, you can use a bonus action to cast the fire shield spell (warm shield only) from it, requiring only verbal components. When you do, you also sprout a pair of flaming wings that last for the duration of the spell and give you a flying speed of 30 feet. Once this property has been used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Call of the Phoenix.</i></b> This helm has 7 charges and regains 1d4 + 3 expended charges daily at dawn. While wearing the helmet, you can expend 1 or more of its charges to cast the following spells from it, requiring only verbal components to do so (save DC 18): <i>death ward</i> (3 charges), <i>flame strike</i> (4 charges), or <i>healing word</i> (2nd-level version, 1 charge; +5 spellcasting ability modifier).</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>From the Ashes.</i></b> If you are reduced to 0 hit points and not killed outright while wearing the helmet, you can use your reaction to call upon the spark of heroism that resides within the galea to drop to 1 hit point instead. When you do, you immediately regain 14 hit points, and each creature within 10 feet of you must make a DC 18 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 4d10 fire damage, or half as much damage on a successful one. In addition, two flaming wings unfurl from your back and carry you to an unoccupied space of your choice up to 60 feet away from you, without provoking opportunity attacks. Once this property has been used, it can't be used again until 2 days have passed. If you die while attuned to this helmet, it vanishes in a cloud of embers and smoke and reappears somewhere in the Elemental Plane of Fire.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Random Properties.</i></b> <i>The Galea of the Soulfire Phoenix</i> has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>1 major beneficial property</li>
				<li>2 minor detrimental properties</li>
				<li>1 major detrimental property</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Destroying the Helmet.</i></b> The only way to destroy the helmet is to feed it to an ancient phoenix. The phoenix dies and is immediately reborn as a result of the intense magic stored within the artifact. When it's reborn, the phoenix has a pronounced crown of golden feathers upon its head. Regardless of how many times it's reborn, the phoenix retains this crown of feathers.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG_ARTIFACT_TABLE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

    <element name="Ionbreaker, the Tempest's Reach" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_IONBREAKER_THE_TEMPESTS_REACH">
		<description>
			<p>This bow was crafted by a powerful djinni in the Stormheart: a perpetual maelstrom of wind and electricity in the Elemental Plane of Air. Lost to time, it has remained in the storm for untold centuries absorbing the volatile magic that runs rampant there. You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>A Storm Is Coming.</i></b> While the bow is on your person, you add a d10 to your initiative at the start of every combat.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Fast as Lightning.</i></b> When you take the Attack action, you can make one attack with the bow as a bonus action.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Discharge.</i></b> A target and any creature within 5 feet of it takes 1d8 lightning damage the first time that target is hit by a ranged attack with the bow on your turn. A creature can only take lighting damage from this property once each round.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Chained Conduits.</i></b> When you hit a target with a ranged attack with the bow, that target becomes a conduit for electricity for 1 minute. You can speak the bow's command word as a bonus action to cause all conduits within 60 feet of you to electrify. When you do, 5-foot-wide lines of electricity arc between all electrified conduits that are within 30 feet of each other. Each conduit takes 2d8 lightning damage, and all other creatures within the lines of electricity must make a DC 18 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d8 lightning damage, or half as much damage on a successful one. Once a conduit has been electrified in this way, it is no longer a conduit. A creature or object can only take lightning damage from this property once each round.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Maelstrom Marksman.</i></b> Once on each of your turns when you miss a target with a ranged attack with the bow, you can reroll the attack against a different target you can see within 30 feet of the first one. You have disadvantage on this attack.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Zephyr Step.</i></b> While holding the bow, you gain a flying speed equal to your walking speed and can hover up to 20 feet off the ground.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Embrace the Storm.</i></b> While you're attuned to the bow, you're subjected to the chaotic magic of the Stormheart whenever you take lightning damage. When you do, roll a d8 and use the table below to determine the resulting effect.</p>
			<h5>title</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="col-10">d8</td><td>Result</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>You are vulnerable to lightning damage until the end of your next turn.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>You are thrown 20 feet in a random direction and knocked prone.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>You are deafened for 1 hour.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>You can't take reactions for 1 minute.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>You cast <i>fog cloud</i>, centered on a point within 5 feet of you, without requiring concentration that remains for 1d4 rounds.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>Up to three random creatures within 10 feet of you take 1d8 lightning damage.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>7</td><td>Your speed is doubled until the end of your next turn.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8</td><td>You are immune to lightning damage until the end of your next turn.</td></tr>
			</table>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Random Properties.</i></b> <i>Ionbreaker, the Tempest's Reach</i> has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>1 minor beneficial property</li>
				<li>1 major beneficial property</li>
				<li>1 minor detrimental property</li>
				<li>1 major detrimental property</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Destroying the Bow.</i></b> The bow can be destroyed if it's struck by lightning in the Stormheart at the same time as it's hit by a hammer of pure adamantine against a similarly adamantine anvil by a creature attuned to the bow. Once destroyed, all creatures within 60 feet of the bow take 10d10 lightning damage and 10d10 force damage. If a creature is reduced to 0 hit points by this damage, it's immediately turned to ash and can only be revived by a wish spell.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG_ARTIFACT_TABLE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longbow">Weapon</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longbow</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

    <element name="Precipit, the Formless - Gas" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_PRECIPIT_THE_FORMLESS_GAS">
		<description>
			<p>This magic coral staff was first found within the Great Reef of the Elemental Plane of Water. Its origins beyond that are entirely unknown, with some suggesting it was made by the plane itself rather than forged or crafted by a mere creature's hands. Attuning to the staff bestows some of its planar powers to you, allowing you to breathe underwater and ignore any of the drawbacks caused by a deep, underwater environment. In addition, while holding the staff, you have resistance to cold damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">This staff has 15 charges which are used to power its various properties. The staff regains 1d8 + 7 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>State Change.</i></b> The staff has a powerful control over the various states of water. As a bonus action while holding the staff, you can mentally command the staff's ever-present bounty of water to change its state into a gas, liquid, or solid. The properties of each state are listed below. Alternatively, you can expend 1 of its charges as a reaction when you are the target of an attack or spell to force the staff to change its state more rapidly. When you do, the staff's change is immediate: potentially affecting the outcome of the incoming attack or spell. You take this reaction when you know you are the target of the attack or spell, but before knowing the result of the roll.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Gas.</i></b> When the staff enters its gaseous state, the water surrounding the staff becomes a fine mist. While holding the staff in this state, you gain the following properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You have resistance to bludgeoning and piercing damage.</li>
				<li>Your movement speed is increased by 10 feet.</li>
				<li>You gain a flying speed equal to your walking speed.</li>
				<li>You can move through the space of any hostile creature, without reducing your movement speed.</li>
				<li>Opportunity attacks against you are made with disadvantage.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Gas Spells.</i></b> While holding the staff in its gas state, you can expend 1 or more of its charges on your turn to cast the following spells (save DC 18) from it: <i>cloudkill</i> (5 charges), <i>fog cloud</i> (1 charge), <i>gaseous form</i> (3 charges), <i>misty step</i> (2 charges), or <i>wind walk</i> (6 charges).</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Tailwind.</i></b> While holding the staff in its gas state, you can expend 2 of its charges and speak the staff's command word as an action to grant additional powers to you and nearby allies. Until the end of your next turn, you and friendly creatures of your choice that you can see within 30 feet of you can take the Dash action as a bonus action and don't provoke opportunity attacks by moving.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Random Properties.</i></b> Precipit, the Formless has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>2 minor beneficial properties</li>
				<li>2 minor detrimental properties</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Destroying the Staff.</i></b> The only way to destroy the staff is to keep it untouched by water for one hundred years while on the Elemental Plane of Water, at which point it crumbles to dust. Any amount, such as a puff of misty air, a drip of water, or the touch of ice during that time reinvigorates the staff's bounty of water.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG_ARTIFACT_TABLE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longbow</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_BLUDGEONING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PIERCING" />
			<stat name="speed" value="10" />
			<stat name="speed:fly" value="speed" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	 <element name="Precipit, the Formless - Liquid" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_PRECIPIT_THE_FORMLESS_LIQUID">
		<description>
			<p>This magic coral staff was first found within the Great Reef of the Elemental Plane of Water. Its origins beyond that are entirely unknown, with some suggesting it was made by the plane itself rather than forged or crafted by a mere creature's hands. Attuning to the staff bestows some of its planar powers to you, allowing you to breathe underwater and ignore any of the drawbacks caused by a deep, underwater environment. In addition, while holding the staff, you have resistance to cold damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">This staff has 15 charges which are used to power its various properties. The staff regains 1d8 + 7 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>State Change.</i></b> The staff has a powerful control over the various states of water. As a bonus action while holding the staff, you can mentally command the staff's ever-present bounty of water to change its state into a gas, liquid, or solid. The properties of each state are listed below. Alternatively, you can expend 1 of its charges as a reaction when you are the target of an attack or spell to force the staff to change its state more rapidly. When you do, the staff's change is immediate: potentially affecting the outcome of the incoming attack or spell. You take this reaction when you know you are the target of the attack or spell, but before knowing the result of the roll.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Liquid.</i></b> When the staff enters its liquid state, the water surrounding the staff becomes a swirling torrent. While holding the staff in this state, you gain the following properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You have resistance to bludgeoning and slashing damage.</li>
				<li>Your movement speed is increased by 10 feet.</li>
				<li>You gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.</li>
				<li>You can stand on and move across any liquid surface as if it were solid ground.</li>
				<li>When a hostile creature that you can see misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to force that creature to repeat the same attack against another creature (other than itself ) of your choice.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Liquid Spells.</i></b> While holding the staff in its liquid state, you can expend 1 or more of its charges on your turn to cast the following spells from it: <i>blur</i> (2 charges), <i>control water</i> (4 charges), <i>create or destroy water</i> (1 charge), <i>mirror image</i> (2 charges), or <i>water breathing</i> (3 charges).</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Tide Turner.</i></b>  While holding the staff in its liquid state, you can expend 3 of its charges and speak the staff's command word as an action to send out a wave of ethereal magic water to buffet and push your enemies. Hostile creatures of your choice that you can see within 30 feet of you are forced to make a DC 18 Strength saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 4d8 bludgeoning damage and is pushed either 20 feet toward you or away from you (your choice). On a successful save, the creature takes half as much bludgeoning damage and is not pushed.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Random Properties.</i></b> <i>Precipit, the Formless</i> has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>2 minor beneficial properties</li>
				<li>2 minor detrimental properties</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Destroying the Staff.</i></b> The only way to destroy the staff is to keep it untouched by water for one hundred years while on the Elemental Plane of Water, at which point it crumbles to dust. Any amount, such as a puff of misty air, a drip of water, or the touch of ice during that time reinvigorates the staff's bounty of water.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG_ARTIFACT_TABLE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longbow</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_BLUDGEONING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_SLASHING" />
			<stat name="speed" value="10" />
			<stat name="speed:swim" value="speed" />
		</rules>
	</element>	

	 <element name="Precipit, the Formless - Solid" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_PRECIPIT_THE_FORMLESS_SOLID">
		<description>
			<p>This magic coral staff was first found within the Great Reef of the Elemental Plane of Water. Its origins beyond that are entirely unknown, with some suggesting it was made by the plane itself rather than forged or crafted by a mere creature's hands. Attuning to the staff bestows some of its planar powers to you, allowing you to breathe underwater and ignore any of the drawbacks caused by a deep, underwater environment. In addition, while holding the staff, you have resistance to cold damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">This staff has 15 charges which are used to power its various properties. The staff regains 1d8 + 7 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>State Change.</i></b> The staff has a powerful control over the various states of water. As a bonus action while holding the staff, you can mentally command the staff's ever-present bounty of water to change its state into a gas, liquid, or solid. The properties of each state are listed below. Alternatively, you can expend 1 of its charges as a reaction when you are the target of an attack or spell to force the staff to change its state more rapidly. When you do, the staff's change is immediate: potentially affecting the outcome of the incoming attack or spell. You take this reaction when you know you are the target of the attack or spell, but before knowing the result of the roll.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Solid.</i></b> When the staff enters its solid state, the water surrounding the staff becomes a frozen shell. While holding the staff in this state, you gain the following properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You have resistance to piercing and slashing damage.</li>
				<li>Your movement speed is reduced to 5 feet.</li>
				<li>You gain a +3 bonus to AC.</li>
				<li>If you're pushed against your will, the distance you are pushed is halved.</li>
				<li>You gain 10 temporary hit points at the start of each of your turns that last until the staff changes state.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Solid Spells.</i></b> While holding the staff in its solid state, you can expend some of its charges on your turn to cast the following spells (save DC 18) from it: cone of cold (5 charges), ice storm (4 charges), ray of frost (no charges, or 1 charge to cast at 5th level; +10 to hit with ranged spell attack), or wall of ice (6 charges).</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Deep Freeze.</i></b> While holding the staff in its solid state, you can expend 4 of its charges and speak the staff's command word as an action to send out a chilling blast to freeze your enemies. Hostile creatures of your choice that you can see within 30 feet of you are forced to make a DC 18 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 4d8 cold damage and its speed is reduced to 0 until the end of its next turn. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much cold damage and its speed is halved instead.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Random Properties.</i></b> <i>Precipit, the Formless</i> has the following random properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>2 minor beneficial properties</li>
				<li>2 minor detrimental properties</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Destroying the Staff.</i></b> The only way to destroy the staff is to keep it untouched by water for one hundred years while on the Elemental Plane of Water, at which point it crumbles to dust. Any amount, such as a puff of misty air, a drip of water, or the touch of ice during that time reinvigorates the staff's bounty of water.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG_ARTIFACT_TABLE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PIERCING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_SLASHING" />
			<stat name="speed" value="-5" />
			<stat name="ac:misc" value="3" />
		</rules>
	</element>

    <element name="Tectonic Gauntlets" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_TEUTONIC_GAUNTLET">
		<description>
			<p>This magical set of stone gauntlets imbue your fists with the power of the Elemental Plane of Earth. While wearing and attuned to the gauntlets, your unarmed attacks become magical and deal 1d8 bludgeoning damage in place of the normal damage of your unarmed strike (unless it's already higher). In addition, these gloves have 15 charges and regain 1d10+5 expended charges each day at dawn. When you make an unarmed attack with your fists, you can expend up to 5 charges to extend your fist's reach by 5 feet for each expended charge. Your unarmed strikes deal double damage to objects and structures.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Powerglove.</i></b> When you hit a target with an unarmed strike, you can expend up to 3 charges to deal an extra 1d8 bludgeoning damage for each charge spent. If you spend any charges in this way, the target must also succeed on a DC 16 Strength saving throw or be pushed back 5 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Geomancy.</i></b> Alternatively, you can expend 1 or more charges on your turn to cast the following spells using the gloves (save DC 16): <i>earthquake</i> (8 charges), <i>move earth</i> (6 charges), <i>shatter</i> (2 charges), <i>spike growth</i> (2 charges, with stone projections), or <i>wall of stone</i> (5 charges).</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Tectonic Plate Armor.</i></b> As an action, you can allow rocks to envelop and protect your body. For 1 hour, you gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage, your movement speed is halved, and you make Dexterity checks and saving throws with disadvantage. You can end this feature early as a bonus action. While enveloped in this way, you can burrow through nonmagical, unworked earth and stone at a speed of 30 feet. While doing so, you don't disturb the material you ove through. If you end this ability while still underground, you're forced out of the earth to the nearest space available and take 1d10 force damage. Once this feature of the gloves has been used, it can't be used again until you take a short or long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Curse.</i></b> Your mind and body become sluggish once you attune to the gloves. The gauntlets become one with your flesh and prevent you from removing them. Your movement speed is reduced by 5 feet, and your Intelligence score is reduced by 4 (to a minimum of 7) while cursed. The curse remains even if the attunement ends but can be undone by any effect that removes a curse such as a <i>greater restoration</i> or <i>remove curse</i> spell, allowing you to remove the gloves and end the curse on you.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Random Properties.</i></b> The gauntlets have the following randomly determined properties:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>1 minor beneficial properties</li>
				<li>1 minor detrimental properties</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Destroying the Gauntlets.</i></b> The gloves can only be destroyed in the depths of the crystalline mines of Durhun on the Elemental Plane of Earth where they were first created.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_WOTC_DMG_ARTIFACT_TABLE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="cursed">true</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="slot">hands</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

    <element name="The Griffon's Saddlebag" type="Magic Item" source="The Griffon's Saddlebag Book 1" id="ID_TGSB_B1_MAGIC_ITEM_THE_GRIFFONS_SADDLEBAG">
		<description>
			<p>These leather bags have the stylized face of a griffon on their front and appear across the multiverse in strange locations. One may be found in the belly of a dragon, while another in the limbs of a great tree. Regardless of where it's found, a <i>Griffon's Saddlebag</i> is typically discovered by an adventurer with a destiny.</p>
			<p class="indent">The saddlebags are made by a great, six-armed griffon on the Astral Plane. Believed by some to be a demigod of pocket dimensions and craftsmen everywhere, the griffon is a patron of artificers and creators across the multiverse. The griffon creates magical items in its great forge using materials collected from various planes of existence to add to its collection. While no one knows exactly how to contact the griffon, it has a knack for knowing what items are needed by whom.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Superior Holding.</i></b> This 1-foot-wide bag always weighs 3 pounds, regardless of what's inside it. It functions as a <i>bag of holding</i> that can only be pierced by another artifact. Placing a <i>bag of holding</i>, <i>handy haversack</i>, <i>portable hole</i>, or similar item inside the extradimensional space created by the saddlebag, or vice versa, destroys the extradimensional item but leaves the saddlebag unharmed. Any item stored within the other extradimensional space is magically moved to the space within the saddlebag instead. If doing so overloads the bag, random contents from either space are scattered in the Astral Plane.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Magic Courier.</i></b> At the GM's discretion, the saddlebag's beak opens up to reveal a letter. The magical script can be read by all creatures with an Intelligence score of 4 or higher. The note is a delivery request or similar that includes the name of an item as well as either specific or vague descriptions of a person or place. At the bottom of the letter is a price listed in coins or other form of payment, as well as a date or time depending on its urgency.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the saddlebag is brought to the described person or place within the allotted time, it dispenses the magical item into the hand of the appropriate recipient. If the payment isn't received by the bag within 1 hour of dispensing the magic item, the item vanishes and is lost. After receiving the payment for an item in this way, the bag's beak reopens to dispense a reward for the courier.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Sell Magic Items.</i></b> The saddlebag has a connection to the griffon's forge on the Astral Plane. Depending on the magic item, you can sell a magic item to the saddlebag for half the cost of its base price.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Spells.</i></b> The saddlebag has 8 charges and regains 1d6 + 2 expended charges daily at dawn. While wearing the saddlebag, you can expend 1 or more of its charges to cast the following spells from it: <i>detect magic</i> (1 charge), <i>identify</i> (1 charge), or <i>legend lore</i> (5 charges).</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Additional Spells.</i></b> At the GM's discretion, such as after reaching certain milestones or completing Magic Courier quests, the saddlebag may offer the following additional spells that can be cast from it: <i>blink</i> (3 charges), <i>dimension door</i> (4 charges), <i>divination</i> (4 charges), <i>etherealness</i> (7 charges), <i>fly</i> (3 charges), <i>magnificent mansion</i> (7 charges), <i>plane shift</i> (7 charges), or <i>secret chest</i> (4 charges).</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Sentience.</i></b> The saddlebag is a sentient chaotic neutral bag with an Intelligence of 13, a Wisdom of 15, and a Charisma of 16. It has hearing and normal vision out to a range of 60 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent">The bag can speak, read, and understand Common. When in the presence of only creatures it trusts, the bag's beak moves when it speaks. Otherwise, the bag communicates telepathically with its wearer. The bag can speak and communicate with griffons.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Personality.</i></b> The bag's purpose is to carry, collect, and deliver magic items. Different bags have different personalities, but they are for the most part largely pleasant to talk to. Their voices are bird-like and are filled with occasional coos and squawks, and their stitched eyes widen, squint, and move expressively.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the bag's wearer or allies fail to fulfill Magic Courier quests, it may stop offering its magic to them. If it does, their items may be lost or inaccessible within the bag, or potentially spat out. While the bag provides the names of item recipients and delivery locations, it doesn't know any more information than what was provided to it by the astral griffon. Regardless, it does its best to help its wearer and allies find the specified person or location on the letter.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Destroying the Griffon's Saddlebag.</i></b> While there is no way to permanently destroy the saddlebag, piercing it with an artifact returns it to its place of origin for repair before it's returned to the multiverse in a new location. Placing a <i>Griffon's Saddlebag</i> inside the extradimensional space created by another <i>Griffon's Saddlebag</i> returns both items to their place of origin and sends all the items stored within them to the griffon's forge on the Astral Plane.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="rarity">Artifact</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
    
</elements>